[Music]
hi and welcome back to 5
shake this week's video is a gelato
recipe it's a gelato messina from
australia
it's the white chocolate version but
we're just going to change it up a
little bit
we're going to do white chocolate with
fudge
covered pretzels and a white chocolate
fudge swirl
so stick around and we'll show you how
to make it
[Music]
so to make this gelato put your milk in
a pan first
and then just slowly bring it up to
around 40 degrees at that point you can
add your dry ingredients so your sugars
and stabilizers etc when that's all in
heat it up to approximately 65 degrees
centigrade
you'll know it's about there if you
don't have a thermometer as that's when
it will start to steam
slightly when it's there hold it at that
temperature for about 30 minutes and
stir it every five minutes or so just to
make sure that nothing sticks to the pan
after half an hour take your ice cream
base pop it in an ice bath and chill it
down
to 40 degrees whilst adding your
chocolate then put it in the freezer
stir it every 10 to 15 minutes until
it's down to 4 degrees centigrade
finally put it in the fridge until
you're ready to churn
[Music]
to make the fudge put your egg and sugar
in one bowl and your chocolate and
butter in the other gently heat the
chocolate and butter in the microwave
it's white chocolate so be gentle
and then whisk all the ingredients
together and then put it aside until
you're ready to use it
finally take your mix out the fridge and
give it a really good whisk
you can use an immersion blender or a
hand whisk like i have
then pop it in your ice cream machine to
[Music]
churn
when your machine's finished churning
you can start layering up your tub
so we've just put a good spoonful of our
white chocolate
fudge sauce in the bottom broken up some
of the
fudge covered pretzels and then just
layer it all in bit by bit when you're
ready
pop it in the freezer this gelato should
be eaten ideally the same day
but if not you know it will last for a
couple of days then it will start to go
a bit funny so
so eat it when it's best
right the tub's been in the freezer now
for quite a while we're just gonna take
it out get some dished up into the bowl
and see what it looks like there we go
it scoops really well
you can see the the chocolate white
chocolate fudge
swirl in there obviously the bits of
what are these called pretzels pretzels
lose my mind
i actually do snack on these it just
made sense just to make an ice cream
flavor out on what does it taste like
the fudge well really works in this
because it's a very sweet
fudge swirl obviously white chocolate is
massive
amounts of sugar in it but
you get that flavor of the white
chocolate come through and you get that
more with gelato because it's much less
fat in it
but this i keep calling it ice cream but
this gelato is a really easy one to make
a kind of all in one pan
if you've never made one before give it
a try
[Music]
really strong white chocolate flavor
those pretzels give a nice bit of crunch
bit of a texture change in there as well
so
anyway i hope you enjoyed this simple
video
and we'll see you next week thanks very
much for watching